个人日志，星历3013.1
Personal log, stardate 3013.1.
过去24小时发生的事让我难以置信
I find it hard to believe the events of the past 24 hours.
史波克在军事法庭的申述也让人难以置信
Or the plea of Mr. Spock, standing general court-martial.
对于非法夺取星舰指挥权
How do you plead to the charge
你认罪吗？
of unlawfully taking command of this starship?
认罪
Guilty.
蓄意破坏星舰电脑系统
Of sabotaging the computers of this vessel
锁定航线，执意前往塔罗斯4号星球？
and locking it on a course for planet Talos IV?
- 认罪 - 劫持派克舰长
- Guilty. - And of forcibly attempting to transport
- 试图将其送至那颗星球？ - 认罪
- Captain Pike to that planet? - Guilty.
为什么？为什么史波克想要把他的前任舰长
Why? Why does Spock want to take to that forbidden world
带到那个禁区？这位刚在空间事故中受了重伤
his former captain, mutilated by a recent space disaster,
现在不成人形，不能说话不能行动的舰长
now a shell of a man, unable to speak or move?
史波克给出的唯一答案就在听审室的屏幕上
The only answer Spock would give was on the hearing-room screen.
至于这是如何做到的，他拒绝予以解释
How Spock could do this, he refused to explain.
但13年前的真实影像，就在我们眼前
But there, before our eyes, actual images from 13 years ago
记录了当年的派克舰长
of Captain Pike as he was when he commanded this vessel,
和那时的史波克
of Spock in those days,
以及进取号如何成为至今唯一
and of how the Enterprise had become the first and only starship
到达过塔罗斯4号星球的星舰
to visit Talos IV.
他们收到从那颗星球发出的遇难信号
They had received a distress signal from that planet
并在那发现多年前失踪飞船的
and discovered there, still alive after many years,
幸存者
the survivors of a missing vessel,
但这一切全是幻觉
only to find it was all an illusion.
没有幸存者，没有营地
No survivors. No encampment.
全是一个陷阱
It was all a trap,
布陷阱的，是一种会制造幻觉的生物
set by a race of beings who could make a man believe
它们制造的幻觉能以假乱真
he was seeing anything they wished him to see.
它们抓走了派克舰长
And Captain Pike was gone,
出于何种目的，还不知晓
a prisoner for some unknown purpose.
我们看的这些影像…
Then the images we've been seeing--
是从塔罗斯4号星球传来的，长官
Are coming from Talos IV, sir.
史波克先生，你了解关于跟塔罗斯4号星球接触的准则
Mr. Spock, you're aware of the orders regarding any contact with Talos IV.
你蓄意触犯了死刑
You have deliberately invited the death penalty.
你明白你在干什么吗？
Do you know what you're doing?
- 你疯了吗？ - 舰长…
- Have you lost your mind? - Captain...
吉姆，求你，不要阻止我
Jim, please don't stop me.
不要让他阻止我
Don't let him stop me.
这关系到你的前途和派克舰长的生命
It's your career and Captain Pike's life.
你必须观看信息的后半部分
You must see the rest of the transmission.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢地航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
TLF荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：刘诗濛 傻得雷
校对：kmdangdangli xjCGI
困兽之斗（下）
审判史波克的军事法庭在封闭的空间中进行
The court-martial of Mr. Spock has been convened in closed session.
不论我们如何防范
Despite all we can do,
影像还是不停从塔罗斯4号星球传来
images continue to be transmitted to us from Talos IV.
星际舰队要求任何人不能和塔罗斯4号接触
Starfleet has ordered no contact with Talos IV.
没有例外
They made no exceptions.
你别无选择，长官，抱歉
You have no choice, sir. I'm sorry.
管理员已经控制了我们的屏幕
The Keeper has taken over control of our screen.
你明白吗，长官？
Do you understand, sir?
正如你们之前所见
As you saw before,
派克舰长被击晕之后
Captain Pike had been knocked unconscious
又被塔罗斯人抓走
and captured by the Talosians.
能听见吗？
Can you hear me?
我是克里斯托弗·派克
My name is Christopher Pike,
星际舰队进取号的指挥官
commander of the space vehicle Enterprise from a stellar group
来自银河系的另一端
at the other end of this galaxy.
我们是为和平而来
Our intentions are peaceful.
你能明白吗？
Can you understand me?
看起来，治安官
It appears, magistrate,
这个样本的智力水平惊人得有限
that the intelligence of the specimen is shockingly limited.
这不奇怪，他的飞船不是轻易就被一条模拟信号
This is no surprise, since his vessel was baited here so easily
给骗了过来
with a simulated message.
读他的心思，就知道
As you can read in its thoughts,
他现在才开始怀疑那些幸存者
it is only now beginning to suspect that the survivors
和营地只是我们在他们大脑里制造的幻觉
and encampment were a simple illusion we placed in their minds.
你没有说话，我却能听见你
You're not speaking, yet I can hear you.
你可以把这解释成我们思维的交换
You will note the confusion as it reads our thought transmissions.
好吧，就是心灵感应
All right then, telepathy.
你们能读懂我的心思，我也能读懂你们的
You can read my mind, I can read yours.
除非你们想让我的船员认为把我抓起来是出于恶意
Unless you want my ship to consider capturing me an unfriendly act--
现在看到的便是原始的“因害怕而威胁”的反应
You'll now see the primitive fear-threat reaction.
标本马上就会开始吹嘘他的能力
The specimen is about to boast of his strength,
他飞船的武器
the weaponry of his vessel,
等等之类
and so on.
下面
Next,
他因为挫败而开始使用他的体力
frustrated into a need to display physical prowess,
他会用自己的身体撞击透明壁障
the creature will throw himself against the transparency.
换做是你，难道就不想试试这墙有多牢吗？
If you were in here, wouldn't you test the strength of these walls too?
肯定有办法出去，我会找到的
There's a way out of any cage, and I'll find it.
尽管受挫，这种生物似乎
Despite its frustration, the creature appears more adaptable
拥有比其他星球标本更强的适应能力
than our specimens from other planets.
我们很快就可以开始实验了
We can soon begin the experiment.
这颗星球的居民住在地下
The inhabitants of this planet must live deep underground,
也许还会生产食物和别的东西
probably manufacture food and other needs down there.
测试表明星球的表面
Now, our tests indicate the planet surface,
植被稀少，动物也很少见
without considerably more vegetation or some animals,
极度贫瘠，根本不适合生物的繁衍
is simply too barren to support life.
所以我们看到的幸存者只是脑中的幻象，史波克先生
So we just thought we saw survivors there, Mr. Spock.
正是，这颗星球的生物给我们制造的幻觉
Exactly. An illusion, placed in our minds by this planet's inhabitants.
完美幻觉
It was a perfect illusion.
他们让我们看到我们想看的一切
They had us seeing just what we wanted to see:
人类勇敢而让人敬佩的幸存者
Human beings who'd survived with dignity and bravery.
一切都合乎逻辑，从营地的建筑
Everything entirely logical, right down to the building of the camp,
褴褛的衣服，所有一切
the tattered clothing, everything.
现在我们必须清楚这次行动的危险性
Now, let's be sure we understand the danger of this.
这个星球的居民能读懂我们的心思
The inhabitants of this planet can read our minds.
他们会根据对方所想，创造幻觉
They can create illusions out of a person's own thoughts,
记忆和经历，甚至欲望
memories and experiences, even out of a person's own desires.
这些幻觉能跟这张桌面一样真实
Illusions just as real and solid as this tabletop,
让人难辨真伪
and just as impossible to ignore.
他们抓走了派克舰长，他需要帮助
It's Captain Pike they've got. He needs help.
只要我们一靠近
If we start buzzing about down there,
我们可能会发现他们强大的精神力量
we're liable to find their mental power is so great,
足以将我们的飞船像苍蝇一样打落
they could reach out and swat this ship as though it were a fly.
激光手枪可能无法将门打破
Now, that entry may have stood up against hand lasers,
但我们可以用飞船的能量来攻击它
but we can transmit the ship's power against it,
足以炸毁半个大陆
enough to blast half a continent.
轮机室负责传输飞船的能量
Engineering deck will rig to transmit ship's power.
我们便能尝试把那块金属炸穿
We'll try blasting through that metal.
我们对这个生物的思维进行了无数测试，治安官
Thousands of us are already probing the creature's thoughts, magistrate.
我们发现他有极好的记忆能力
We find excellent memory capacity.
我感知到他对最近的一次生死决斗记忆最为强烈
I read most strongly a recent death struggle
记忆中，他为自己的生命而战
in which it fought to protect its life.
就从这个记忆开始
We will begin with this,
给这个标本一些更有意思的东西去保护
giving the specimen something more interesting to protect.
快，我们必须藏起来
Come on. We must hide ourselves.
快，快
Come. Come.
快啊
Hurry.
那儿没人，没准有武器和食物
It's deserted. There'll be weapons and perhaps food.
这里是参宿七星球
This is Rigel VII.
求你了，我们必须藏起来
Please, we must hide ourselves.
我被关在笼子里，一个监狱，就像动物园
I was in a cage, a cell, in some kind of a zoo.
- 我肯定还在原地 - 快啊
- I must still be there. - Come on.
他们进了我的思维
They've reached into my mind
借助我的记忆，让我重返旧地
and taken the memory of somewhere I've been.
克莱人！
The Kaylar!
和两周前发生的事情一模一样
It's starting just as it happened two weeks ago.
除了你
Except for you.
派克舰长出色的推理，各位
A brilliant deduction by Captain Pike, gentlemen.
是的，他的确还在牢房里
Yes, he was still inside his cell.
- 但也无能为力 - 那些塔罗斯人控制了他的大脑
- But knowing that couldn't help him. - The Talosians controlled his brain.
把他带到任何地点，任何时间
And could make him live any place, any time,
任何他们设置的场景
any situation they wished.
他能看见，能感觉
He would see, taste,
经历真实的遭遇，就像各位坐在这里一样真实
suffer, with the same reality as you gentlemen sitting there.
头发长了，不一样的衣服，但的确是你
Longer hair, different dress, but it is you,
那位名叫维娜的幸存者
the one the survivors call Vina.
或者说，维娜的幻象，但是为什么又是你？
Or rather, the image of Vina. But why you again?
他们为什么不创造另一个女孩？
Why didn't they create a different girl?
快，如果你趁它不注意的时候攻击…
Quick. lf you attack while it's not looking...
但这只是一个梦
But it's only a dream.
你必须杀掉他，就像你之前一样
You have to kill him, as you did here before.
你去和看守讲，我是不会照做的
You can tell my jailers I won't go along with it.
我不是为了获得晚餐而表演的动物
I'm not an animal performing for its supper.
不论你怎么说，你能感受一切，这才是关键
It doesn't matter what you call this. You'll feel it. That's what matters.
你可以感受每一刻所发生的一切
You'll feel every moment of whatever happens to you.
结束了
It's over.
她是谁？他们为什么停止传输影像了？
Who is she? Why have they stopped the images?
因为他们知道派克舰长累了
Because they know that Captain Pike is fatigued.
我们一会儿再继续
We can reconvene later.
看来他们还是关心舰长的
Then they care about the captain.
他们想要他活着回去，长官
They want him back. Alive, sir.
- 我需要知道为什么 - 如果你耐心点，答案…
- I demand to know why. - If you'll be patient, the answers to--
你忘了你是在接受审判，史波克
You're forgetting you're on trial, Spock.
你必须回答所有问题
You will answer all questions put to you.
我的答案让人难以置信，长官
My answer to your question would be quite unbelievable, sir.
很遗憾你必须耐心自己去看
I regret we'll have to wait and see it there.
个人日志，星历3010.2
Personal log, stardate 3013.2.
对史波克的军事审判重新开始
Reconvening court-martial of Mr. Spock
星舰上有史以来最奇怪的证物也再次
and the strangest trial evidence ever heard aboard a starship.
从那颗离我们只有1小时路程的星球传来
From the mysterious planet now only one hour ahead of us,
关于派克舰长在关押期间的故事
the story of Captain Pike's imprisonment there.
你为何在此？
Why are you here?
取悦你
To please you.
你是真实的吗？
Are you real?
- 跟你想地一样真实 - 噢，不
- As real as you wish. - Oh, no.
不，那不是我要的答案
No, that's not any answer.
我从未遇到过你，从未想过你
I've never met you before, never even imagined you.
也许他们从你遗忘的梦里找到我
Perhaps they made me out of dreams you've forgotten.
是么？然后让你穿跟他们一样的金属纤维衣服？
What, and dressed you in the same metal fabric they wear?
我可以穿任何你喜欢的衣服
Or I can wear whatever you wish.
变成任何你想要的样子
Be anything you wish.
然后他们就可以观察标本的反应？
So they can see how their specimen performs?
他们想看我如何反应，是吗？
They want to see how I react, is that it?
你难道就不曾梦过
Don't you have a dream,
某件你极其渴望的东西？
something you've always wanted very badly?
难道他们不仅仅想观察我？
Or do they do more than just watch me?
他们…
Do they...
还能感受我的感受？
...feel with me too?
你可以拥有任何你想要的东西
You can have whatever dream you want.
我可以成为任何人
I can become anything,
任何你想要的女人
any woman you've ever imagined.
整个宇宙，你想要什么便能拥有什么
You can have anything you want in the whole universe.
让我…
Let me...
满足你
...please you.
是的，是，你可以取悦我
Yes, yes, you can please me.
你可以跟我讲他们的事情
You can tell me about them.
有什么办法可以让我阻止他们看穿我的心思
Is there any way I can keep them from probing my mind
阻止他们利用我的思维控制我？
and from using my thoughts against me?
你害怕了？
Does that frighten you?
也就是说有办法？
Does that mean there is a way?
你是个笨蛋
You're a fool.
既然你不是真实的
And since you're not real,
我们也没必要再继续聊了，对吧？
there's not much point in continuing this conversation, is there?
- 线路安装完毕，史波克先生 - 待命，大副
- All circuits engaged, Mr. Spock. - Standing by, Number One.
- 找掩护 - 10、9、8
- Take cover. - Ten, nine, eight,
7、6、5
seven, six, five,
4、3、2、1
four, three, two, one.
增至最大能量！
Increase to full power!
还能再大些吗？
Can you give us any more?
电路开始发热了，必须停止火力
Our circuits are beginning to heat. We'll have to cease power.
停火！
Disengage!
那个小山包一开始就该被铲平
The top of that knoll should've been sheared off the first second.
也许早就被铲平了
Maybe it was.
这就是我在简报室想说的事
It's what I tried to explain in the briefing room.
他们制造幻觉的强大精神力量使我们无法确认任何所做之事
Their power of illusion is so great, we can't be sure of anything we do
或看见的任何东西
or anything we see.
或许你来问我些问题
Perhaps if you asked me some questions,
我能解答
I could answer.
他们能把我的思想控制到什么程度？
How far can they control my mind?
如果我告诉你，你能挑选一个过去的梦
If I tell you, then will you pick some dream you've had,
然后让我跟你一起在里面生活吗？
and let me live it with you?
也许吧
Perhaps.
他们不能让你做不愿意做的事
They can't actually make you do anything you don't want to.
但他们会用幻觉引诱我去做
But they try to trick me with their illusions.
你抵抗的话，他们还会惩罚你
And they can punish you when you're not cooperative.
你很快就能找到答案
You'll find out about that.
他们曾经在地面上生活过吗？
Did they ever live on the surface of this planet?
他们为什么来到地下？
Why did they go underground?
战争，几千个世纪以前
War. Thousands of centuries ago.
地上为何如此贫瘠？
That's why it's so barren up there?
这个星球才刚恢复适宜生命繁衍的状态
The planet's only now becoming able to support life again.
所以塔罗斯人到地下之后发现活动范围有限
So the Talosians who came underground found life limited here,
就开始专心发展精神力量
and they concentrated on developing their mental power.
他们发现这是个陷阱
They found it's a trap,
就像毒品
like a narcotic.
因为当梦比现实更重要的时候
Because when dreams become more important than reality,
人们不再旅行，建造，发明
you give up travel, building, creating.
甚至连怎么修
You even forget how to repair the machines
那些祖先留下的机器都忘了
left behind by your ancestors.
他们什么都不做，只靠别人的记忆生活
You just sit, living and reliving other lives
虚幻的生活
left behind in the thought records.
或者研究一下像我这种“动物标本”的思维
Or sit probing the minds of zoo specimens like me.
对你的观察远不止看戏这么简单，他们为你制造幻觉
You're better than a theatre to them. They create an illusion for you,
看你的反应，体会你的情绪
they watch you react, feel your emotions.
他们收集了一整套标本
They have a whole collection of specimens,
都是很久以前带回来的生物的后代
descendants of life brought back long ago
来自银河系各个地方
from all over this part of the galaxy.
也就是说每种生物至少收集一对
Which means they had to have more than one of each animal.
- 别再说了 - 他们收集的人类也要一对
- Please. - They'll need a pair of humans too.
他们打算去哪儿找那个女的呢？
Where do they intend to get the woman?
你说过如果我回答你的问题…
You said that if I answered your questions--
但我是在和一个虚幻的东西讨价还价
But that was a bargain with something that didn't exist.
你说过你不是真实的，记得吗？
You said you weren't real, remember?
我是个女人…
I'm a woman...
跟你一样真实
...as real and as human as you are.
我们就像亚当和夏娃
We're like Adam and Eve.
如果我们…
If we...
不要！求你了！
Don't! Please!
不要惩罚我！我尽力了！
Don't punish me! I tried!
一个来自地球的女人
An Earth woman.
你被当成种畜抓了起来？
Then you were captured as breeding stock?
为什么？
Why?
只为保持动物园里标本的供应吗？
Just to maintain a supply of zoo specimens?
远不止此，舰长
Much more, captain.
瓶子里是一种营养蛋白复合物
The vial contains a nourishing protein complex.
动物管理员在跟他养的动物交流？
Is the Keeper actually communicating with one of his animals?
如果食物的样子和颜色不合适
If the form and the colour is not appealing,
我可以让它变成你想吃的任何食物
it can appear as any food you wish to visualise.
- 如果我情愿…？ - 饿着？
- And if I prefer--? - To starve?
你忘了不合作就会被惩罚
You overlook the unpleasant alternative of punishment.
来自你小时候听过的神话故事
From a fable you once heard in childhood.
你现在赶紧吃掉营养液
You will now consume the nourishment.
为何你不能让我的大脑产生饥饿的念头？
Why not just put irresistible hunger in my mind?
因为你不能，是吗？
Because you can't, can you?
你能力的确有限，是吗？
You do have limitations, don't you?
如果你再不听话
If you continue to disobey,
在你的脑海里
from deeper in your mind,
还有让你更痛苦的事
there are things even more unpleasant.
真有意思
That's very interesting.
现在说说那个女的
Now to the female.
你刚才被吓到了，你不是会读心术吗？
You were startled. Weren't you reading my mind then?
如你猜测的那样
As you've conjectured,
一艘地球飞船在我们的星球上坠毁，只有一个幸存者
an Earth vessel did crash on our planet, but with only a single survivor.
现在，回到之前的话题
Now, let's stay on the first subject.
我当时想用双手掐住你的脖子
All I wanted for that moment was to get my hands around your neck.
我们治好了幸存者的伤
We repaired the survivor's injuries,
发现这种生物很有意思
and found the species interesting.
是不是原始的思绪能阻止你洞察人心？
Do primitive thoughts put up a block you can't read through?
这变成必须要吸引一个男性
It became necessary to attract a mate.
好吧，好吧，我们就聊聊那个女孩
All right, all right, let's talk about the girl.
你似乎煞费了苦心让她变得魅力十足
You seem to be going out of your way to make her attractive,
想让我因此产生保护的欲望
to make me feel protective.
为了保持物种繁衍，必须这样
This is necessary in order to perpetuate the species.
我接受她喜欢她似乎对你更重要
It seems more important to you now that I begin to accept her and like her.
我们希望我们的标本能在这儿过得开心
We wish our specimens to be happy in their new life.
假设这是个谎言
Assuming that's a lie,
你为什么想我喜欢她？
why would you want me attracted to her?
这样我才能体会夫妻间的那种爱？
So I'll feel love in a husband-wife relationship?
除非想成家，才会这样做
That'd be necessary only if you intend to build a family group,
整个人类社会都是这样
or perhaps a whole human community.
- 在雌性被适当处理的情况下 - 你是说适当惩罚的情况下！
- With the female properly conditioned. - You mean properly punished!
是我不听话，你为什么不惩罚我？
I'm the one who's not cooperating. Why don't you punish me?
先是情感的防范
First, an emotional protectiveness.
现在又是同情
Now, one of sympathy.
很好
Excellent.
亲爱的，来点咖啡？
You want some coffee, dear?
我把热水瓶挂在马鞍上了
I left the Thermos hooked to my saddle.
探戈
Tango.
你这个老家伙
You old devil, you.
抱歉，我身上没带…
I'm sorry, I don't have any s--
好吧，他们考虑得还真周到
Well, they think of everything, don't they?
- 回到家感觉很棒吧？ - 他们真算得上“脑子”里的蛔虫
- Is it good to be home? - They read our minds very well.
家，还有我想要的任何东西
Home, anything else I want,
前提是我合作，是吗？
if I cooperate, is that it?
天啊，这还真是美好的一天，不是吗？
My, it turned out to be a lovely day, didn't it?
你回家了，甚至可以留在家里，如果你愿意
You're home. You can even stay, if you want.
但是，我们俩并不在这儿
But we're not here, neither of us.
- 我们只是在一个动物园的笼子里 - 不要！
- We're in a menagerie, a cage. - No!
如果你不给我机会的话，我谁都帮不了
I can't help either one of us if you won't give me a chance.
你告诉过我，他们把幻觉当麻醉剂
You told me once they used illusions as a narcotic.
他们甚至不能修好祖先留下来的机器
They couldn't even repair the machines left by their ancestors.
这就是他们需要我们的原因吗？
Is that why they want us?
- 来建立一个满是奴隶的殖民地？ - 别说了！
- To build a colony of slaves? - Stop it!
难道你不关心他们会怎么对我们吗？
Don't you care what they'll do to us?
在笼子里的时候，好像有那么几分钟
Back in my cage, it seemed for a couple of minutes
“饲养员”不能读取我的心思
that our keeper couldn't read my thoughts.
像仇恨那样的感情，在脑海中集中起仇恨
Do emotions like hate, keeping hate in your mind,
这样他们的读心术就不会奏效了？
does that block off our mind from them?
对，他们无法读取原始情感
Yes. They can't read through primitive emotions.
但是你不能坚持足够久的，我试过了
But you can't keep it up for long enough. I’ve tried.
他们就年复一年地纠缠你，戏弄你，惩罚你
They keep at you and at you, year after year, tricking you, punishing.
他们就赢了
And they won.
我现在是他们的了
They own me.
你肯定会因此而讨厌我
I know you must hate me for that.
不，我并不讨厌你
Oh, no, I don't hate you.
我能想到那是怎样的经历
I can guess what it was like.
这还不是全部
That's not enough.
难道你没有发现吗？
Don't you see?
他们读取我的心思，我的感受
They read my thoughts, my feelings,
还有我梦中的白马王子
my dreams of what would be the perfect man.
这就是他们选择你的原因
That's why they picked you.
我不得不爱你
I can't help but love you.
他们也期待你和我有同样的感受
And they expect you to feel the same way.
如果他们能读取我的心思，他们就会知道我被你深深吸引着
If they can read my mind, then they know I’m attracted to you.
从在幸存者营地看见你的第一眼起
I was from the very first moment I saw you in the survivor's camp.
你就像个狂野的小动物
You were like a wild little animal.
我终于开始明白为什么这些对你都没用了
I'm beginning to see why none of this has worked for you.
在家里，在参宿七战斗
You've been home and fighting, as on Rigel.
这些对你都不陌生
That's not new to you either.
而得不到的永远在骚动
A person's strongest dreams are about what he can't do.
是的，对于一位舰长
Yes, a ship's captain.
总是得正式
Always having to be so formal,
得体、可靠、礼仪周全
so decent and honest and proper.
你一定很想知道，没有这些束缚是什么样子
You must wonder what it would be like to forget all that.
美妙的地方，派克先生
Nice place you have here, Mr. Pike.
维娜？
Vina?
那又是维娜？
That's Vina again?
变成了绿色的猎户座女奴？
As the green Orion slave girl?
她们就像野兽，堕落又迷人
They're like animals. Vicious, seductive.
她们说没有人类的男性能抵挡住其诱惑
They say no human male can resist them.
来自过去的奇怪证据
Strange evidence from the past.
为了繁育一个把人类当奴隶的社会
How the Talosians, planning to breed a society of human slaves,
塔罗斯人用他们囚禁的地球女子引诱派克舰长
tempted Captain Pike with the Earth woman they held in captivity.
她以多种面貌出现在他面前
And as she appeared to him in many forms,
一次比一次性感
each more exciting than the last,
派克开始动摇了
Pike was beginning to weaken.
设想你的选择千千万万
Suppose you had all of space to choose from,
而这只是一个小小的样本
and this was only one small sample.
难道你不觉得这值得一个男人出卖其灵魂吗？
Wouldn't you say it was worth a man's soul?
你们都知道现在的状况了
Well, you all know the situation.
希望我们能直接传送到塔罗斯人的地盘里
We're hoping to transport down inside the Talosian community.
如果我们的测量读数也是幻觉的话
If our measurements and readings are an illusion also,
你可能会发现自己出现在一块坚石里
one could find oneself materialized inside solid rock.
如果谁想退出，没人会责怪的
Nothing will be said if any volunteer wants to back out.
女人！
The women!
舰长
Captain.
舰长？
Captain?
不要！让我做完呀！
No! Let me finish!
但我们是一行六人才对，只有我们被传送过来了
But we were a party of six. We were the only ones transported.
这不公平，你不需要她们
It's not fair. You don't need them.
用不了
They don't work.
我们出发时能量可是充满的
They were fully charged when we left.
没用，发不出信号
It's dead. I can't make a signal.
- 这是怎么回事？ - 别说话
- What is it? - Don't say anything.
现在我的脑海中是一幅把他们畸形的大脑袋打成肉酱的画面
I'm filling my mind with a picture of beating their misshapen heads to pulp,
原始情感，这样他们就把一切都中断了
thoughts so primitive they black out everything else.
我在脑海里积聚着仇恨
I'm filling my mind with hate.
你能把思想阻滞多久？
How long can you block your thoughts?
几分钟？一小时？
A few minutes? An hour?
- 你觉得有用吗？ - 别打扰他
- How can that help? - Leave him alone.
他不需要你，他已经选择了我
He doesn't need you. He's already picked me.
选择了她？为什么？我不懂
Picked her? For what? I don't understand.
为了高智商后代，他真应该选你
Now there's a fine choice for intelligent offspring.
后代？孩子吗？
Offspring? As in children?
后代就是说，他是亚当，对吗？
Offspring as in, he's Adam. Is that it?
你也没有好多少
You're no better choice.
他们还不如让他和电脑在一起
They'd have more luck crossing him with a computer.
好吧，要不我们来做个简单的计算题？
Well, shall we do a little time-computation?
那时的探险队名单上有个叫维娜的成年女子
There was a Vina listed on that expedition as an adult crewman.
现在，我们加上18年，就会…
Now, adding 18 years to your age then...
这不公平！我照你的要求做了
It's not fair! I did what you asked.
既然你拒绝了之前的样本
Since you resist the present specimen,
你现在多了几个选择
you now have a selection.
我总会突破这笼子来到你面前的
I'll break out of this zoo somehow and get to you.
我倒要看看你的血是不是和我们的一样红
Is your blood red like ours? I'm gonna find out.
这两个新样本有她们各自的优点
Each of the two new specimens has qualities in her favour.
这位你称之为“大副”的女性头脑更出众
The female you call "Number One" has the superior mind,
会产出高智商的后代
and would produce highly intelligent children.
我唯一想做的就是亲手捉到你
All I want to do is get my hands on you.
你能读到这些想法吗？
Can you read these thoughts:
仇恨杀戮的画面？
Images of hate, killing?
另一个新来的
The other new arrival
一直以为你遥不可及，但现在意识到了转机
has considered you unreachable, but now is realising this has changed.
她的优势是青春活力
The factors in her favour are youth and strength,
加上异常强烈的女性魅力
plus unusually strong female drives.
你会发现我的思想更有意思
You'll find my thoughts more interesting.
你不懂的原始情感
Thoughts so primitive you can't understand.
丑恶的情感…
Emotions so ugly--
错误的思想会自食苦果
Wrong thinking is punishable.
正确的思想会即刻得到奖励
Right thinking will be as quickly rewarded.
你会发现这是个有效的组合
You will find it an effective combination.
- 舰长… - 不，不用管我
- Captain-- - No, no, don't help me.
我必须得集中精力
I have to concentrate.
他们不能读透仇恨
They can't read through hate.
- 老实点，否则我… - 别伤害他
- Hold still or I'll-- - Don't hurt him.
他们并不是坏人
They don't mean to be evil.
他们多么善良我可是如数家珍
I've had some samples of how good they are.
把这幻觉停下，否则我直接把你脑袋拧下来
You stop this illusion or I'll twist your head off.
好了
All right.
你要是再尝试新的幻觉，哪怕丁点半点
Now, you try one more illusion, you try anything at all,
我就拧断你的脖子
and I'll break your neck.
你的星舰
Your ship.
放开我
Release me...
否则我们就毁了它
...or we'll destroy it.
他没有虚张声势，舰长
He's not bluffing, captain.
利用幻觉，他们会让你的船员出现误操作
With illusion, they can make your crew work the wrong controls
或者按下某个按钮，只要能毁掉你的舰船
or push any button it takes to destroy your ship.
我打赌你们这么智慧的生物不会毫无理由地杀戮
I'm gonna gamble you're too intelligent to kill for no reason at all.
不过，我这里有个理由了
On the other hand, I've got a reason.
我打赌你又创造了一个激光枪没有能量的幻觉
I'm willing to bet you've created an illusion this laser is empty.
我觉得刚才那个窗户已经被打出了一个洞
I think it just blasted a hole in that window
你在从中作梗让我们看不见
and you're keeping us from seeing it.
你是不是要我在你的脑袋上检验我的理论呢？
You want me to test my theory out on your head?
舰长！
Captain!
看来塔罗斯人抛弃了你
It seems the Talosians have deserted you.
先生们，请稍等一会
Gentlemen, a moment, please.
史波克？
Well, Mr. Spock?
- 您有裁决了吗？ - 是您希望他们停止讯号的
- May I have your verdict? - Signal you want them to wait.
舰长，拜托了，这关系到您的生命，至少给生命一次机会
Captain, please. It's your life now. At least a chance for life.
史波克，你总是在谈生命，给生命一次机会
You keep talking about life, Mr. Spock, a chance for life.
怎样的生命？当一个囚徒？
How? As a prisoner?
关在笼子里？当一个动物园的标本？
Caged? A zoo specimen?
在幻觉中生活，以取悦他的管理员？
Living the illusions that amuse his keepers?
不，舰长，不仅仅只有这么多
No, captain. There's more to it.
看吧
Watch.
有罪？是或否，舰长
Guilty? Yes or no, captain.
有罪
Yes.
我必须也投“罪名成立”
I must also vote "guilty as charged."
你呢，舰长？
And you, captain?
罪名…
Guilty...
成立
...as charged.
舰桥呼叫指挥官
Bridge to commander.
- 这里是门德兹 - 长官，我们正在进入塔罗斯四号的轨道
- Mendez here. - Sir, we're entering orbit, Talos IV.
长官，塔罗斯现在控制着这艘舰船，就像他们十三年前一样
Talos controls the vessel now, sir, as they did 13 years ago.
你们问过我原因，现在你们就能看到答案
You've asked me why. You'll see the answer now.
取得联络，大副
Make contact, Number One.
他们也不让我们看到这个
They kept us from seeing this too.
我们接通了却根本不知道
We cut through and never knew it.
舰长
Captain.
你也看到了，你想出逃的努力毫无结果
As you see, your attempt to escape accomplished nothing.
我想联络我的舰船
I want to contact our ship.
你现在就在星球表面，也就是我们希望你生活的地方
You are now on the surface, where we wished you to be.
和你选择的女性一起
With the female of your choice,
你现在可以开始精心规划好的生活
you will now begin carefully guided lives.
就从把你埋葬开始吗？
And start by burying you?
那是你自己的选择
That is your choice.
为了帮助你重新开垦这星球表面
To help you reclaim the planet surface,
动物园会提供各种各样的植物生命
our zoological gardens will furnish a variety of plant life.
好吧，我和你来做个交易
Look, I'll make a deal with you.
你的命换这两位地球女性的生命
You and your life for the lives of these two Earth women.
你证明我的舰船完好无损，把她们俩送回去
You give me proof that our ship is all right, send these two back,
我就会和维娜留下来
and I'll stay with Vina.
创造一整个奴隶般生活的人类种族是错误的
It's wrong to create a whole race of humans to live as slaves.
这是一个骗局吗？
Is this a deception?
- 你想自我毁灭吗？ - 这是怎么回事？
- Do you intend to destroy yourselves? - What is that?
这武器会累积到过载，带来强力的爆炸
The weapon is building up an overload, a force chamber explosion.
你还有时间回到地下去
You still have time to get underground.
好了，快走吧
Well, go on!
就给你看看人类有多么原始，塔罗斯人
Just to show you how primitive humans are, Talosian...
你和她一起走
...you go with her.
如果你们觉得这如此重要
If... If you all think it's this important,
那么我也不能走
then I can't go either.
我觉得如果他们有一个人类，就可能会再次尝试
I suppose if they have one human being, they might try again.
等等
Wait.
他们存储记录的技术很粗糙，花了很多时间
Their method of storing records is crude and consumed much time.
你准备好吸收了吗？
Are you prepared to assimilate it?
我们一直以为这不可能
We had not believed this possible.
你们种族的习俗和历史表明你们对奴役的仇恨是独一无二的
The customs and history of your race show a unique hatred of captivity.
即使安逸舒适
Even when it's pleasant and benevolent,
你们却宁死不从
you prefer death.
对我们的需求来说，你们这个物种太凶暴，太危险了
This makes you too violent and dangerous a species for our needs.
他的意思是他不能用你了
He means that they can't use you.
你现在可以自由地回到舰船了
You're free to go back to the ship.
就这样了
And that's it.
连句道歉都没有
No apologies.
你们俘虏了一个人，却威胁了我们所有人
You captured one of us, threatened all of us.
你的不相称已经宣告了塔罗斯族的死刑
Your unsuitability has condemned the Talosian race to eventual death.
这还不够吗？
Is this not sufficient?
没有其他样本展示了你这样的适应能力
No other specimen has shown your adaptability.
你是我们最后的希望
You were our last hope.
但不会是某种形式的交易
But wouldn't some form of trade,
互助合作…？
mutual cooperation...?
你们的种族也会习得我们制造幻觉的能力，并最终自我毁灭
Your race would learn our power of illusion and destroy itself too.
舰长，我们有传送器信号了
Captain, we have transporter control now.
我们回舰上去吧
Let's get back to the ship.
我不能
I can't.
我不能和你们一起走
I can't go with you.
长官，它自动启动了，没办法停下
Sir, it just came on. We can't shut the power off.
- 这里是史波克 - 所有能量都启动了，史波克
- Mr. Spock here. - All power's come on, Mr. Spock.
船舵正在回应控制
The helm is answering to control.
舰长
The captain.
你明白我为何不能跟你一起走了吧
You see why I can't go with you.
这才是这位女性的真实面貌
This is the female's true appearance.
他们在残骸里发现了我，奄奄一息
They found me in the wreckage, dying,
只是一坨肉而已
a lump of flesh.
他们改造了我，一切正常
They rebuilt me. Everything works.
但是他们从来没有见过人类
But they had never seen a human.
他们不知道怎么把我复原
They had no guide for putting me back together.
很有必要让你确信，她想留下的决定是诚实的
It was necessary to convince you her desire to stay is an honest one.
你会再次给她美貌的幻觉
You'll give her back her illusion of beauty.
不仅如此
And more.
史波克，系统又启动了
Mr. Spock, the system is coming on again.
- 维娜呢？ - 她不和我们一起走吗？
- What's happened to Vina? - Isn't she coming with us?
不了
No.
而且我认同她的理由
No, and l agreed with her reasons.
- 所有甲板人员准备超空间飞行 - 所有甲板人员准备好了，长官
- All decks prepare for hyperdrive. - All decks are ready, sir.
出发
Engage.
准将，你不认为…
Commodore, don't you think that...?
寇克舰长，你现在听到的
What you now seem to hear, Captain Kirk,
是我的思维传输
are my thought transmissions.
准将从来没有登上你的舰船
The commodore was never aboard your vessel.
他的存在只是幻觉，不管是那里还是在穿梭机上
His presence there and in the shuttlecraft was an illusion.
史波克先生已经告知我们你强大的意志力
Mr. Spock had related to us your strength of will.
我们认为，虚构一个军事法庭审判
It was thought the fiction of a court-martial
会转移你的注意力，以免你很快重新掌控舰船
would divert you from too soon regaining control of your vessel.
我们很欢迎派克舰长和我们共度余生
Captain Pike is welcome to spend the rest of his life with us,
从他那副躯壳中解脱
unfettered by his physical body.
这是你们的，也是他的决定
The decision is yours and his.
史波克，即使条例很明晰
Mr. Spock, even if regulations are explicit,
你还是可以来我这里解释清楚
you could've come to me and explained.
请你也来面对极刑？
Ask you to face the death penalty too?
一个人就够了，舰长
One of us was enough, captain.
- 是的 - 长官，来自星际基地11号的信息
- Yes. - Message from starbase 11, sir:
“收到了来自塔罗斯四号星球的影像
"Received images from Talos IV.
鉴于派克舰长在太空探索中的历史重要性
In view of historic importance of Captain Pike in space exploration,
一般手则第七条，即禁止与塔罗斯四号星接触
General Order 7, prohibiting contact Talos IV,
在这种情况下暂时失效
is suspended this occasion.
针对史波克的行动没有任何诉讼
No action contemplated against Spock.
请酌情妥善处理”
Proceed as you think best."
署名，门德兹，准将，星际基地11号
Signed, Mendez, J. I., commodore, Starbase 11.
克里斯
Chris...
你想去吗
...do you want to go there?
史波克
Mr. Spock...
你可以把派克舰长带到传送室吗？
...would you care to take Captain Pike to the transporter room?
为他送行
See him off.
谢谢您，长官
Thank you, sir.
代表我们俩
For both of us.
史波克，完事之后
Mr. Spock, when you're finished,
请回来见我，我想和你谈谈
please come back and see me. I wanna talk to you.
你最近展现出的令人遗憾的
This regrettable tendency you've been showing lately
公然的情绪化倾向
towards flagrant emotionalism...
长官，没有理由去侮辱我
I see no reason to insult me, sir.
我相信我在整件事中都是完全合符逻辑的
I believe I’ve been completely logical about the whole affair.
寇克舰长
Captain Kirk.
派克舰长拥有幻想
Captain Pike has an illusion,
你则拥有现实
and you have reality.
愿你旅途愉快！
May you find your way as pleasant.
本集结束
-=The Last Fantasy=-
谢谢观赏